Finding aid to the F. Warren Wright Papers CA.MS.00068
Smith College Archives
F. Warren Wright Papers
1880-1966
Smith College Archives
Wright, Frederick Warren, 1885-
CA.MS.00068
4.583 linear feet (11 containers)
Professor, classics. Contains biographical data, Classical Association of New England bulletins, correspondence, diaries, educational records, lectures, photographs, publications and research.
Biographical / Historical
Frederick Warren Wright was born in Middletown, Rhode Island to the Reverend William Arter Wright and Sarah Elizabeth Longley Wright on March 8, 1885. He had one older sister named Bertha. He earned his A.B. in Classics from Wesleyan University in 1906, his A.M. from Harvard in 1908 and his Ph.D. from Princeton in 1910. His dissertation was titled "Studies in Menander." In 1915 Professor Wright married Louise Marion Fisher, a graduate of Vassar and of Teachers' College, Columbia University. Mrs. Wright taught physical education at Smith and was the director of the day school.
Professor Wright was always an educator, but his first job, when he was not engaged in his studies at Wesleyan or Harvard, was as a reporter for the Chautauqua Daily in New York. His first position in a school was as the Assistant Principal of a high school in Portland, Connecticut, and then as a lecturer in Latin at Bryn Mawr. Professor Wright came to Smith in 1911 as an Instructor in Latin. He was made assistant professor in 1914, associate professor in 1920 and professor in 1937. In 1942 he was appointed Chair of the Classics Department. Professor Wright also served as Marshal between 1925 and 1947 and as a member of the Board of Admissions from 1934 until his retirement in 1953.
Professor Wright's scholarly interest concerned ancient drama and theater, and he published a number of articles, and one book, titled Cicero and the Theater (1931), on this topic. His articles were published in the Classical Journal, Journal of Classical Philology, Classical Weekly and the American Journal of Philology. He traveled extensively throughout Europe and the Mediterranean for his research of ancient theater sites. Professor Wright was also a member of several professional organizations including the Archaeological Institute of America, the American Classical League, the Classical Association of New England, the American Association of University Professors, the Classical Society of the American Academy in Rome, the Association Guillaume Bude, The Socratic Literary Society and Phi Beta Kappa. He was also a member of the Hampshire County Red Cross and the Northampton Kiwanis Club.
Professor Wright died on July 31, 1966.
Scope and Contents
The Wright Papers include biographical data, Classical Association of New England bulletins, correspondence 1879-1953, diaries, educational records, Kiwanis Club material, lectures, photographs, publications and research, Smith College records, speeches and war service. Much of the collection is composed of letters between Professor Wright and his mother, Sarah Longley Wright between the years of 1894 and 1938. The Wright Papers also include files on William Arter Wright, Sarah Longley Wright and Louise Marion Fisher Wright. Among Louise Wright's files are sketch books, letters and photographs.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The F. Warren Wright Papers came to the college as a series of donations from Professor Wright, and from his Estate.
Wright, Frederick Warren, 1885-; Wright, Louise Fisher.; Wright, Sarah Longley.; Smith College--Faculty.; Classical Association of New England.
- General (Box 1094, Folder 1)
- Association of Begatees of Clergy (Box 1094, Folder 2)
- Biographical Data (Box 1094, Folder 3)
- Classical Assoc. of New England, 1902-1936 (Box 1094, Folder 4)
- Classical Assoc. of New England, 1938-1949 (Box 1094, Folder 5)
- Classical Assoc. of New England, 1950-1955 (Box 1094, Folder 6)
- Classical Assoc. of New England, 1956-1959 (Box 1094, Folder 7)
- Diaries, 1931-1951 (Box 1094, Folder 8)
- Diaries, 1964-1966 (Box 1094, Folder 9)
- Education
  - Ontario Public School (Box 1095, Folder 1)
  - Riverside Public Schools, 1891-[1899] (Box 1095, Folder 2)
  - Jamestown Business College, 1890 (Box 1095, Folder 3)
  - Jamestown High School, Dec. 20, 1901 (Box 1095, Folder 4)
  - Chaffey College, 1897-1964 (Box 1095, Folder 5)
  - Wesleyan University, 1902-1964 (Box 1095, Folder 6)
  - Harvard University, 1907-1908 (Box 1095, Folder 7)
  - Princeton University, 1908-1913 (Box 1095, Folder 8)
- Italy, 1931-1933 (Box 1095, Folder 9)
- Kiwanis Club, 1934-1963 (Box 1095, Folder 10)
- Lectures, Apr. 18, 1927 (Box 1095, Folder 11)
- Leonard Discussion Group, 1935-1943 (Box 1095, Folder 12)
- Northampton Tercentenary, 1954 (Box 1095, Folder 13)
- Out But Not Down Club, 1960 (Box 1095, Folder 14)
- Obituaries, 1966 (Box 1095, Folder 15)
- Retirement, 1953 (Box 1096, Folder 1)
- Smith College, 1911-1952 (Box 1096, Folder 2)
- Speeches, 1930-1952 (Box 1096, Folder 3)
- War Service, 1918-1942 (Box 1096, Folder 4)
- Wright, Louise (Fisher), 1906-1947 (Box 1096, Folder 5)
- sketchbook belonging to L.F.W., 1914 (Box 1096)
- sketchbook belonging to L.F.W., 1946-1948 (Box 1096)
- Wright, Sarah (Longley) (Box 1096, Folder 6)
- Wright, William Arter (Box 1096, Folder 7)
- Correspondence
  - Correspondence - General (Box 1097, Folder 1)
  - Abott, Senda (Berenson), undated (Box 1097, Folder 2)
  - Collins, Elizabeth & Frank, 1962-1964 (Box 1097, Folder 3)
  - Dean, Sidney Norton, 1942-1943 (Box 1097, Folder 4)
  - Fisher, Charles Irving, 1915-1924 (Box 1097, Folder 5)
  - Freeman, Frank & Bertha, 1903-1953 (Box 1097, Folder 6)
  - Freeman, John & Evelyn, 1930-1963 (Box 1097, Folder 7)
  - Freeman, T. Fred & Daniel Roy, 1897-1943 (Box 1097, Folder 8)
  - Ganong, William Frances, Mar. 24, 1933 (Box 1097, Folder 9)
  - Heidel, W. A., 1908-1933 (Box 1097, Folder 10)
  - McCann, William Sharp & Gertrude (Fisher), 1956-1965 (Box 1097, Folder 11)
  - Meyerhoff, Howard Augustus, Sep. 18, 1944 (Box 1097, Folder 12)
  - Neilson, Elizabeth (Muser), 1946 (Box 1097, Folder 13)
  - Patch, Howard Rollin, 1926 (Box 1097, Folder 14)
  - Penner, Albert J., Mar. 12, 1934 (Box 1097, Folder 15)
  - Rankin, Frances (Freeman), 1937-1964 (Box 1097, Folder 16)
  - Ransom, Pearl E., 1941-1947 (Box 1097, Folder 17)
  - Richardson, Mary Lilias, Mar. 16, 1914 (Box 1097, Folder 18)
  - Rooke, Margaret LeBreton, Mar. 15, 1925 (Box 1097, Folder 19)
  - Shields, Emily Ledyard, Mar. 11, 1947 (Box 1097, Folder 20)
  - Turlington, Bayly, 1958-1965 (Box 1097, Folder 21)
  - Wilder, Inez (Whipple), Sep. 8, 1926 (Box 1097, Folder 22)
  - Wright, F. Warren (copies of letters sent out), 1959-1964 (Box 1097, Folder 23)
  - Wright, Louise Fisher (to and from), 1914-1915 (Box 1097, Folder 24)
  - Wright, Louise Fisher (to and from), 1916-1930 (Box 1097, Folder 25)
  - Wright, Louise Fisher (to and from), 1931-1949 (Box 1097, Folder 26)
  - Wright, Louise Fisher (to and from), 1950-1963 (Box 1097, Folder 27)
  - Wright, Sarah (Longley)
    - 1894-1898 (Box 1098, Folder 1)
    - 1899-1901 (Box 1098, Folder 2)
    - 1902-1903 (Box 1098, Folder 3)
    - 1904 (Box 1098, Folder 4)
    - 1905 (Box 1098, Folder 5)
    - 1906 (Box 1098, Folder 6)
    - 1907-1908 (Box 1098, Folder 7)
    - 1908-1909 (Box 1099, Folder 1)
    - 1910 (Box 1099, Folder 2)
    - 1911 (Box 1099, Folder 3)
    - 1912-1913 (Box 1099, Folder 4)
    - 1914 (Box 1099, Folder 5)
    - 1915 (Box 1099, Folder 6)
    - 1916 (Box 1099, Folder 7)
    - 1917-1918 (Box 1100, Folder 1)
    - 1919-1920 (Box 1100, Folder 2)
    - 1921-1923 (Box 1100, Folder 3)
    - 1924-1925 (Box 1100, Folder 4)
    - 1926-1927 (Box 1100, Folder 5)
    - 1928-1929 (Box 1100, Folder 6)
    - 1930-1931 (Box 1100, Folder 7)
    - 1932-1938 (Box 1100, Folder 8)
- Photographs
  - 1880-1900 (Box 1101, Folder 1)
  - 1901-1910 (Box 1101, Folder 2)
  - 1911-1920 (Box 1101, Folder 3)
  - 1921-1930 (Box 1101, Folder 4)
  - 1931-1940 (Box 1101, Folder 5)
  - 1941- (Box 1101, Folder 6)
  - Photographs - Fisher family, undated (Box 1101, Folder 7)
  - Photographs - Wright, William Arter and Sarah (Longley), 1901-1915 (Box 1101, Folder 8)
  - Six photograph albums, 1910-1923 (Box 1102)
  - Two photograph albums, 1920; 1950 (Box 1103)
- Publications, General, 1911-1962 (Box 1104, Folder 1)
- Fashions in Girls' Names at Smith College, 1954 (Box 1104, Folder 2)
- Research - ancient theaters
  - A-E (Box 1104, Folder 3)
  - G-Z (Box 1104, Folder 4)
  - England and Spain (Box 1104, Folder 5)
  - France (Box 1104, Folder 6)
  - Italy (Box 1104, Folder 7)